XINLEI ZHANG

RESEARCH INTERESTS & GOAL

My research interests lie in the **theories** and **applications** in **robotics**, including **state estimation** & **system dynamics**, **nonlinear control**, and **reinforcement learning**. My goal is to advance robotics research by integrating artificial intelligence and control theory methods.

EDUCATION

1 South China University of Technology | Intelligent Manufacturing

09/2020 - 06/2024 (Expected)

Shien-Ming Wu School of Intelligent Engineering

Q Guangzhou, China

Overall GPA

Related Courses

- Applied Calculus II 96/100, Linear Algebra 97/100, Probability and Statistics 89/100
- Artificial Intelligence Technology and Applications 90/100, Data Structure 91/100
- Sensor Technology and Applications 90/100, Mechatronics 92/100
- System Dynamics 91/100, Classical Control Theory 92/100

PUBLICATION & PATENT

On Ambiguity in 6-DoF Magnetic Pose Estimation 6 | First Author

08/2023

3.75/4.0

Xinlei Zhang, Shuda Dong and Heng Wang

Submitted to IEEE Transaction on Robotics (T-RO), under the first-round review

A Virtual Ultrasonography Simulator for Skill Training Using Magnetic-Inertial Probe Tracking 03/2023 Heng Wang, Shuangyi Wang, Suqi Liu, Shuda Dong, Xinlei Zhang

CN Patent Pending, No.CN116312122A &

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

The Lab of Magnetic-Controlled Robot, SCUT *Research Assistant*, advised by Dr. Heng Wang **9**

09/2021-Present

6-DoF Magnetic-Inertial Pose Estimation

09/2021-12/2021

- Innovation & Significance: While most existing magnetic pose estimation systems consist of multiple magnetic sources, only one magnetic source is required in our work. 6-axis inertial and 3-axis magnetic measurements of the target were fused to estimate its pose with uncertainties in sensor measuring and magnetic source modeling. This technology could be applied to robotic systems requiring millimeter-degree-scale accuracy.
- Contribution: I participated in this project in **developing the 6-DoF pose estimation algorithm**, using the **state estimation technique (extended Kalman filter)**. During this project, I found the ambiguity issue in measurement systems and proposed this issue as my next research project.
- Outcome: 1.) one CN patent which is under pending; 2.) one new research project.

On Ambiguity in 6-DoF Magnetic Pose Estimation

01/2022-Present

- Innovation & Significance: In the last project, the system failed to provide 6-DoF estimation without the 6-axis inertial sensor. In this project, I fundamentally investigated the ambiguity issue in magnetic pose estimation systems, including its definition, categorization, identification algorithm and impact on pose estimation, which could serve as a theoretical framework to analyze the ambiguity issue in any system. The most compact and energy-efficient 6-DoF Pose Estimation system with only two magnetic sources was proposed. One equation was derived revealing the dynamical nature behind the ambiguity issue.
- Contribution: I undertook this project, and investigated the ambiguity issue in the theoretical level. I developed identification algorithms for ambiguous poses and provided computer simulation verification. Moreover, I designed and conducted experiments to demonstrate all my findings.
- Outcome: 1.) One academic manuscript has been submitted to IEEE Transaction on Robotics (T-RO); 2.) This project has earned recognition and funding through the Chinese National Training Program of Innovation and Entrepreneurship for Undergraduates, with a total funding amount of \$1300.

Tendon-Driven and Flex Sensor Based Gesture Sensing Hand Exoskeleton 6 Team Leader Spring 2023

- 10 motors are controlled to stretch tendons attached to the hand exoskeleton, achieving independent control of all five fingers. Moreover, flex sensors are fixed with fingers to measure their bending extent, providing gesture information, to construct the closed-loop gesture control of fingers.
- **Key words:** PID Motor Control, 3D Modeling and Manufacturing of Exoskeleton, Tendon-driven Mechanism, Bending Sensor, Closed-loop Gesture Tracking.

An Efficiency-Optimal Automated Assembly Line for the Luban Lock **O** | Team Leader Spring 2023

- Genetic algorithm, an evolutionary Optimization algorithm, was employed to find the efficiency-optimal scheduling of nine production machines of one assembly line, which was a Flexible Job Shop Problem.
- Key words: Flexible Job Shop Problem, Genetic Algorithm, Plant Simulation.

Wireless-Powered Animation System Displayed by Rotating LEDs & Team Leader

fall 2022

- Multiple embedded system modules, motor-driving, infrared-monitoring, wireless-charging and sounding-effect, were controlled to present the **self-designed animation** based on the principle of persistence of vision.
- **Key words:** Wireless-charging Coil & Circuit Design, Infrared Sensor, Sounding Module, Animation Presented by Rotating LED Stripe.

Omni-Motion, Bluetooth-control and Self-Reloading Automatic Catapult 🚱 | Team Leader Spring 2022

- The **kinematic model** of the 4 omni-wheel motion was analyzed to achieve the **omni-direction control**. Remote operation was achieved using the **Bluetooth** device and **one self-designed android app**. Moreover, a self-reloading mechatronics device was developed by **3D printing**, **laser cutting and circuit design** technologies.
- **Key words:** Omni-motion UGV Design and Manufacturing, Bluetooth Module & Android App, Self-reloading Mechanism, Lever-Spring-Motor Shooting Mechanism.

Machine Learning & IMU Based Classifier on Ping-Pong Players' Motion 🔗 Team Leader Fall 2021

- Neural network and decision tree classifiers were ensembled to distinguish the motion of forehand drive and backhand stroke of a Ping-Pong player based on the inertial data. Moreover, One-class SVM and Local outlier factor were employed to detect wrong motions during training which may bring damage to the player's wrist.
- **Key words:** Inertial Sensor, Classifier: Neural Network & Decision Tree, Fault Detection: One-class SVM & Local Outlier Factor, Ping-Pong Training Monitoring.

Selected Awards & Honors &

Mathematical Contest in Modeling

05/2023

Honorable Mention (Second-Class Award), Top 30%

Alibaba Cloud Programming Contest in SCUT

03/2023

Third-Class Award, Top 15%

Undergraduate Internship Scholarship, China Scholarship Council & University of Alberta

08/2022

Only 1 in South China University of Technology and total 9 in China

National Contest on Micro Sensing and Intelligent Technology

10/2021

National First Prize & Excellent Defense, Top 4%

South China University of Technology Student Scholarship

Freshman Year

Third-Class University Scholarship, 7/55

OTHER-RESEARCH-ACTIVITIES

Journalist Volunteer for School Invited Academic Speeches

03/2023-Present

I write 5-minute reading summary news of academic speeches for School Social Media Public Account

Student Memberships of many famous academic research communities

2022-Present

Student memberships of IEEE CSS, RAS, and virtual academic seminars hosted by CMU and UoT

SKILLS

Languages: Chinese (Native), English (Fluent)

Programming: MATLAB & Simulink, Python, C, C++, R

Others: SolidWorks, CAD, Embedded System Development, Photo & Video Editing, LaTeX & Markdown